MODESTAS RIMKUS

FRONT END DEVELOPER

INFO

ADDRESS

Vilnius, Lithuania

PHONE

+37067642259

EMAIL

mr.modestas.rimkus@gmail.com

LINKS

<u>LinkedIn</u>

<u>GitHub</u>

SKILLS

HTML & CSS

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ

SASS

 \bullet \bullet \circ \circ

JavaScript

• • • 0 0

React JS

 \bullet \bullet \circ \circ

React Native

• • 0 0 0

React-redux

• • 0 0 0

HOBBIES

Photography Mountain biking Skiing

LANGUAGES

English

• • • • 0

Russian

• • 0 0 0

PROFILE

I'm a determined, self-taught Front-end developer with one plus years of experience of coding. Currently I'm in the search of an entry-level position where I can enhance my skill set to be a hard-working asset to any team. Dedicated to learning additional technologies and coding languages (currently enrolled in a Full-stack course). I'm able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate in a team setting.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

2nd line support, UAB "Tele2"

Vilnius

2017 - 2020

- · Resolved technical incidents and complaints escalated from 1st line support
- · Maintained procedures of insurance and warranty service products
- · Deputy of insurance service product owner
- · Curator of Northeast Tele2 stores

UAB "Transcom Worldwide Vilnius"

Vilnius

2014 - 2015: Customer service specialist (telecommunication services):

 Handled incoming calls, with duties including explaining customer bills, payment issues, presenting relevant product and service information

2015 - 2017: Win-back specialist and sales representative:

- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Retained clients and extended contracts by addressing issues and concerns
- · Trained new hires and mentored more junior colleagues
- · Effectively multitasked: built and maintained team's local intranet website

EDUCATION

Bachelor's degree in finance, Vilniaus Kolegija / University of Applied Sciences

Vilnius

2012 - 2015

Kretinga Franciscan Gymnasium

Kretinga

2000 - 2012

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Žemaičio žodis (https://github.com/mopixels/Zemaicio-zodis)

Android was app created by using **React Native**. For this application I used functional components (used *hooks*), for state management I used **React Redux**.

Addresser (https://github.com/mopixels/addresser)

Web app was created by using **JavaScript** framework **React JS**, styled with **SCSS** preprocessor. Elements were named by using **BEM**. Website is **responsive**, it adapts to different screen sizes.

MTB Time (https://github.com/mopixels/MTB_Time)

Website built with ${\bf HTML5}$ and ${\bf CSS3}$, for styling used ${\bf SCSS}$. Although this is one-pager, SASS code is broke down to components as much as possible.